[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；扬声器1：有一个关于能够冻结数据对象的问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: There's a question about being able to freeze data objects.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：你可以，除非你有什么东西，否则我不推荐
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: You can, I don't recommend it unless you have something
真的想保持不变。
that really wants to be immutable.
记住，一旦你冻结了一些东西，你就不能解冻它。
Remember that once you freeze something you can't unfreeze it.
所以你只走一条路。
So you're only going one way.
&gt；&gt；扬声器1：然后让我们看看，日期和JSON。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: And then let's see, Dates and JSON.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：不，JSON完成了。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Nope, JSON's done.
&gt；&gt；扬声器1：是的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Yeah.
不好吧。
Well, no okay.
所以你只是没有推荐的格式？
So you just don't have a recommended format?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：JavaScript没有，所以JSON没有。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: JavaScript didn't have one so JSON didn't get one.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：使用时间戳？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Use timestamp?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，我建议使用ISO字符串。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yep, I'd recommend using ISO Strings.
这似乎是最聪明的事情。
That seems to be the smartest thing.
我知道有很多人不喜欢做最聪明的事情，所以
I know there are lot of people who don't like doing smartest things, so
他们可以随心所欲。
they're free to do whatever they want.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 4：您对JSON[INAUDIBLE]规范有什么看法
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: What's your take on the JSON [INAUDIBLE] spec that's been
最近到处走动吗？
going around recently?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：对于Java？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: For Java?
&gt；&gt；扬声器4：不，它是[INAUDIBLE]和
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: No, it's a [INAUDIBLE] and
这是一种为[INAUDIBLE]服务器格式化JSON admins的方式。
it's being kinda way to format JSON admins for [INAUDIBLE] server.
算法内部如何组织数据的基本集合。
Basic collection of how you organize data inside the algorithm.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：我不知道。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I'm not aware of it.
任何人都可以自由地做任何他们想做的事。
Anybody is free to do anything they want.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：线程和错误。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Thread and bugs.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：不，不幸的是，他们也可以自由这么做。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: No, unfortunately they're free to do that too.
&gt；&gt；扬声器5：[笑]&gt；&gt；扬声器6：为什么你没有
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Speaker 6: Why don't you have
对斯威夫特的看法？
an opinion on Swift?
你只是看得不够吗，还是-&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我
Have you just not looked at it enough, or- &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I've
看得不够。
not looked at enough.
我去拿斯威夫特的报告
I went to get the Swift report and
它被隐藏在一些苹果登录的东西后面，并且说地狱。
it was hidden behind some Apple login thing and said hell with that.
所以我没拿到。
So I didn't get it.
所以我不了解最新情况。
So I'm not up to date on it.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：你不用骆驼壳的原因是什么？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: What's the reason you don't use camel case.
[听不见]
[INAUDIBLE].
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以有一个很大的争论，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So there's this big debate,
在任何语言中做多单词标识符的正确方法是什么？
what is the correct way to do multi-word identifiers in any language?
您是应该使用骆驼大小写还是应该使用under bar和
Should you use camel case or should you use under bars and
这是另一个程序员不能达成一致的事情，
this is another one of those things that programmers can't agree on,
你知道会有没完没了的争论。
that you know there's an endless argument.
有一个无休止的争论为什么它永远不会结束，
And the reason there is an endless argument why it will never end,
是因为他们都错了。
is because they are both wrong.
正确的做法应该是使用空间，
That the correct thing should have been to use space,
我们的语言只需要变得更聪明一点，我们可以有空格
that our languages only have to get a tiny bit smarter and we could have spaces as
名字中的有效字符，然后他们会读得更好
valid characters inside of names and then they would read better and
他们会更容易，处理和所有这些东西。
they'd be easier to, to, process and all of that stuff.
所以除了获取数字之外，我在下一门语言中寻找的一个方面
So one of the aspects I'm looking for in the next language besides getting numbers
对，就是它也允许空格作为名字的组成部分。
right, is that it'll also allow space as a component of names.
&gt；&gt；扬声器7：那是角度还是角度2？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 7: That's in Angular or Angular 2?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：很多角度或角度2。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Lots of angular or angular two.
这是两个完全不同的问题。
That's two completely different question.
&gt；&gt；扬声器7：或者？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 7: Either or?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我看过棱角和
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I've looked at angular and
我有点惊讶于让事情变得容易是多么的困难。
I was kind of surprised at how hard it is to get to make something easy.
我不明白。
I don't get it.
我从那些信誓旦旦的人那里听到的
I hear from people who swear by it and
我认为这很棒，也许它解决了他们的问题。
I think that's great and maybe it solves the problem they have.
我没有观察到这解决了我的问题。
I've not observed that solves a problem that I have.
&GT；&GT；演讲者8：这是斯德哥尔摩的事情，我认为是有棱角的，一旦你到了那里。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 8: It's the Stockholm thing, I think with angular, once you get there.
&gt；&gt；扬声器7：是的。这太棒了。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 7: Yeah. This is great.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所有这些框架的问题是
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Well the problem with all these frameworks is that
一旦你得到承诺，你就被困住了。
once you get committed you are stuck.
你不能去，那是个错误，退后。
You can't go, that was mistake and back off.
你完全投入了
You're fully committed and
所以，在你做出承诺之前，你无法发现这些事情中的任何一件是好还是不好。
so, you can't find out if any of these things are good or not until you commit.
所以你必须小心。
And so you have to be careful.
&gt；&gt；演讲者3：所以我从Github到Douglas Crawford.com和
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So I went from Github to Douglas Crawford dot com and
你显然没有低CSS。
you clearly have no low CSS.
[笑]那里没有CSS
[LAUGH] There's no CSS on there.
[听不见]什么？
[INAUDIBLE] What?
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：什么？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: What?
&GT；&GT；演讲者3：你对C.S.有什么问题？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: What's your issue with C.S.S.?
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：你会再次提起那个旧伤口吗？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Are you going to bring up that old wound again?
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：先生，是的&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：所以C.S.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Sir I, Yeah &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So C.S.S.
是为格式化技术文档而设计的，这是它生活中的目的。
was designed for formatting technical documents that was its purpose in life.
这不是我们使用它的形式，我们将它用于各种非常
And that is not what we use it form, we use it for all kinds of stuff that is very
非常适合，我们使用它是因为它是唯一的选择。
badly suited for and we use it because it's the only option.
而且它比它出现之前要好，因为在过去没有
And it's better than it was before it came along because in the past there were no
过去人们通过使用微小的小尺寸来进行排版间距的选项
options used to see people doing typographic spacing by having tiny little
其中有一点点空白
that with a little bit of white space in them which
被认为是当天的最佳实践，但总是一件可怕的事情。
was considered a best practice on the day but was always a terrible thing to do.
所以，相比CSS是伟大的，但与我们应得的相比，它是可怕的。
So, compared to that CSS is great but compared to what we deserve it's awful.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：你仍然可以使用一些HTML，对吧，我的意思是-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: You can still use some HTML, right, I mean-
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：是的，那也是。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah That too.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：[笑]&gt；&gt；扬声器9：任何意见
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Speaker 9: Any opinions
关于生锈的语言？
on the rust language?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：不，我没有，我读过他们的一些材料。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: No, I don't, I have read some of their material.
它没有被锁在苹果密码后面，所以我读了一些
It wasn't locked behind an Apple password so I have read some of that and
其中一些看起来很有希望，但我还没有得出任何结论。
some of it looks promising but I don't have any conclusions yet.
我没有和它合作过。
I've not worked with it.
&gt；&gt；演讲者1：趋势，桩和，我的意思是，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: What about trends, pilers and, I mean,
你有什么建议或者-&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：那么
do you have any recommendations or- &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So
让我说一下CoffeeScript，它引发了这股热潮。
let me say this about CoffeeScript, which started this craze.
我非常喜欢CoffeeScript。
I like CoffeeScript a lot.
CoffeeScript使JavaScript的一些好的部分更加明显。
CoffeeScript makes some of the good parts of JavaScript more visible.
对于一些人来说，如果他们学会了，学习如何很好地使用JavaScript会更容易
For some people it's easier to learn how to use JavaScript well if they learn
咖啡脚本也是。
CoffeeScript also.
我认为我最喜欢CoffeeScript的一点是
I think the thing I like best about CoffeeScript
它看起来不像C，或者Java，或者任何其他语言。
is that it doesn't look like C, or Java, or any of those other languages.
它有自己的外观。
It's got its own look.
过去人们常说，任何新的编程语言都不可能成功，除非它
It used to be said that no new programming language could succeed unless it
看起来像C.
looked like C.
in CoffeeScript表明这不再是真的
In CoffeeScript is showing that that's no longer true
CoffeeScript之所以成功，是因为它看起来不像C。
CoffeeScript succeeds because it doesn't look like C.
所以，我非常喜欢。
So, I like that a lot.
那么问题是，你应该在生产中使用CoffeeScript吗？
Then the question is, should you use CoffeeScript in production?
绝对不行。
Absolutely not.
不，您不应该在生产中使用CoffeeScript。
No, you should not use CoffeeScript in production.
它仍然是一种实验性的语言，它增加了很多奇怪的东西。
It's still an experimental language it adds a lot of weirdness.
这使得招聘人员变得更加困难，因为
It makes it harder to recruit people because
谁来写一些潮人留下的CoffeeScript东西。
who's gonna write the CoffeeScript stuff that some hipster left.
只是不值得。
It's just not worth it.
所以，我总是建议学习这门语言。
So, I always recommend learn the language.
学习一门新的语言
Pick up a new language and
有些拼写的语言很有趣，值得学习。
some of the transpiled languages are interesting, and are worth to study.
但我不建议在生产中使用它们中的任何一个。
But I don't recommend using any of them in production.
我认为，他们没有增加足够的价值来证明这种怪异。
I think, they don't add enough value to justify the weirdness.
&gt；&gt；演讲者8：非常感谢，并且
&gt;&gt; Speaker 8: Lots of thank yous, and
请表达他们对培训的感激之情。
please extend their gratitude for the training.
你找到了吗-&gt；&gt；扬声器1：是的，有人问
Do you find anymore- &gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Yes, somebody asking
有没有什么原因让你禁用了关于你的Get Up项目的bug报告。
is there a reason that you disabled bug reports on your get up projects.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：我没有那样做。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I didn't do that.
什么，我抱怨起来没有
What, I have complained to get up that there is no
我试着用正确的方式来表达，我倾向于吸引巨魔。
I'm trying to think of it the right way to say this, I tend to attract trolls.
我不知道为什么，但是
I don't know why this is, but
有很多人真的很想来我现在的地方
there are a lot of people who really want to come on to where I am and
做一些粗鲁的行为，这不仅令人讨厌，而且是浪费时间。
do trollish behavior, which is more than annoying, it's a waste of time.
我必须处理巡逻，我不喜欢这样做。
I have to deal with the patrols and I don't like having to do that.
所以我要求Git Hub提供一个没有巨魔的选项。
So I've asked Git Hub for a no troll option.
到目前为止，他们还没有想出如何实现这一点。
And so far they have not figured out how to implement that.
所以有些事情我已经关闭了，但并没有完全关闭，
So there are some things that I've turned things off but it's not completely off,
你还是可以给我留言的。
you can still get messages to me.
但如果你曾经骚扰过我，我会把你放在封锁名单上，所以这可能是他的担忧。
But if you have trolled me, I put you on the block list so that may be his concern.
他过去可能曾经骗过我，但现在他不能骗我了。
He may have trolled me in the past but he can't troll me now.
[笑]所以我不会为此道歉
[LAUGH] So I'm not gonna apologize for that.
&gt；&gt；演讲者1：你对构建系统有什么看法吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Did you have any opinions on build systems?
你提到了连接的做法，以及所有这些东西。
You mentioned practices of concatenating, and all that stuff.
他们在说网络包之类的东西。
They're saying things like web pack or whatever.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：不，我不在乎，只要管用就行。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: No, I don't care, whatever works.
&gt；&gt；扬声器1：是的，我就是这么想的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I figured.
看不到任何其他问题。
Not seeing any other questions.
房间里有人吗？
Anybody in the room?
你最后一次得到意见的机会[笑]好吧。
Your last chance to get an opinion [LAUGH] all right.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：我想我们被判了死刑。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I think we're adjurned.
&gt；&gt；演讲者1：结束，对。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Concluded, right.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：谢谢。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Thank you.